that you do not need a mentor you need
some someone to grow with you right and
like that that's something that a lot of
beginners uh have trouble with is that
oh I need someone to learn from and
that's not the fact like you need
someone to learn with yes in order to
grow up together and I think that's the
best best part of hacking when you can
just you know critical things right
right hey
[Music]
anything
okay like 30 seconds before we started
recording just just say that again for
the for the mic yeah I I never watched
the podcast so I don't know what we're
going to talk about
come on man you're killing me I'm just
kidding of course
um all right guys we're here we're in
Japan
that's awesome the live live hacking
event is uh is a is a wrap and uh yeah
we've just been relaxing for the past
couple I don't know if you'd call it
maybe relaxing we've been doing some
pretty intense sightseeing the hiking
was not relaxing yeah yeah
um but yeah what did you guys what did
you guys think of the live hacking event
any any Lessons Learned or takeaways we
wanna we wanna share
man I I thought that the live hacking
event was uh really cool in Tokyo and
everything I think like the lesson I
learned is a how to pick fights you know
uh in a way that
um there is some bugs where you need to
argue more than others and you do not
have the time to argue on every bird
bugs while when you're on the live
hacking event scene so uh we need to
really pick like what are the most
impactful bugs and which one do you take
time to explain to the program and which
one do you just kind of quit arguing
about it so that was a good lesson I
think yeah absolutely I mean some of the
some of the bugs that can come out of
this event especially the things that
were shown at Show and Tell were some of
the most unexpected things I'd say like
I was very surprised at like honestly a
lot of them were very like simple
straightforward like things definitely
in hindsight I was like oh I should have
just yeah I'm surprised I didn't see
that or you know whatever it is
um and some of them were just like
insanely big brained like yeah
um I don't want to go into too many
details but there was one one with like
uh you would put like the same parameter
in twice and I we just probably just
would have never even tried anything
like that I I mean that like a lot of
the bugs were um simple technically but
you needed to find how to do it and so
this is like the frugality of uh back
Wednesday when you find like something
really easy to reproduce but at the same
time you need to be recreative about how
you find those kind of bugs and so there
is a lot of people that went the actual
miles in the Recon because we had like a
small scope and there was so much out of
the box thinking and it's really
inspiring to see the show entails yeah
man that was that was the thing for me
on this one I I have a lot of I have a
lot of takeaways from this one
um it was it was a little bit of a
challenging one for me personally so I
was sitting in the in the hot bath with
uh with an ugly last night kind of uh
you know running over what kind of stuff
that we could have done differently
and just like you guys said you know
there there were just a lot of bugs at
this event that were just like wow
um you you know why would you even try
that you know like and and uh so
definitely thinking out of the box and
then I think another another really
thing that became really clear to me
this event was
um you know the the team made it very
clear that like if you are able to
impact core components in pii that they
don't they don't care like you know like
you you that is what they want you know
and so scope is not not a problem at
that point right as long as their users
are getting protected
um which I think is really great but
it's something that I didn't prioritize
quite as well you know during this event
and and I think um the hackers that that
went around the scope and then found
ways to uh you know attack the core
assets in in pii I think they did the
best this this event that's really
impressive yeah yeah and I think one of
the interesting things we actually
talked about this like last week on the
last episode about where is sort of the
ethical boundary about going out of
scope and like yes is it okay to go out
of scope if it provides impact and I
think one sort of caveat to this is it
wasn't really like out of scope per se
it was it was more like out of scope for
the event it would be in scope for the
main program and I think like worst case
scenario if you'd really gone like out
of scope
but they were really looking for things
that would cause impact to this to this
you know special scope that was being
targeted and and just in general to to
the program as a whole and so I think it
was really awesome that they were they
said that was okay for you to you know
sort of bend it a little bit as long as
you're able to provide impact because
that they have that awesome relationship
with the researchers I think that every
company should do that uh when they have
the maturity because
um like I don't like scope in the sense
of domains right but I like scope about
the sense of where you are impacting the
data right so in my opinion scope
shouldn't be like uh there is this
subdomain that is code but the other one
is not the scope imagine that you have a
subdomain that is exposed you do not
even know about and there is direct link
to the database with a SQL injection
this is the same database that is
impacted with the same data but it
wouldn't be in scope and so I prefer
when program says for instance the core
database is in scope but we do not care
about the entry point right and there is
other programs that are really mature
about third third parties because uh
European companies actually if there is
a third party leaking data or anything
they are still responsible the first
part is always responsible and um and so
it's really cool when you you can you
know hunt on third parties also so I I
really wish we had more maturities in
that realm you know yeah it's definitely
it's definitely cool to see and I think
um you know like you said that's
something that's a more mature program
decision but it's really awesome to see
and it actually makes the most sense
from a technical perspective too because
like you run into these programs where
it's like okay this domain is in scope
okay well what the heck does that mean
because nine times out of ten that
domain is resolving 2009 P that's a load
balancer and that load balancer serves
many different applications so if you're
saying okay this IP is in scope well
then I can modify the host header on
that specific request to get routed to
all sorts of different applications from
those in scope you know
um and so it's cool to see a program you
know like you said take responsibility
as the the first party
um and and do that
um the other the other big takeaway for
me from this event was
um I guess very thoroughly at auditing
JavaScript files that are not
necessarily on the main asset you know
and um and for me one of the things that
I I knew before this event and I
actually did but didn't thoroughly
assess uh was lazy loaded uh webpack
files right
um interesting and so uh you know going
that extra mile to uh you know open up
the core main.js file dump all of the uh
you know dynamically loaded JavaScript
files that are also you know in that
same folder grabbing all those down and
then making sure you're thoroughly
auditing all those to get uh the API all
the API resources you need
um you know that that was that would
have made a big difference for me during
this episode yeah and like it's very
it's very counterintuitive because if
you're hacking on that app and you look
at it in burp you say you just go to a
login page you're not gonna see all of
the other modules being loaded because
they're lazy loaded it's only going to
load the things that are necessary and
so if you just see oh there's this JS
file and you just see only a couple
little endpoints or whatever that and
that's it that you're you have to go you
have to explicitly start to pull apart
those JavaScript files and you're going
to find the other functionality because
it's in there you just have to go and
get it and if you don't log in or
something say it's an admin portal right
you can't log in well you might not see
those but they're there and if you go
deeper you may actually be able to
access things within those files and
you'll see the other functionality but
it'll take more time and something like
JS weasel I think you know we've talked
about this before you know tools like
like that are designed for analyzing
JavaScript functionality those are
really going to come into play as more
and more like react apps and that kind
of stuff that are doing this type of
behavior come into play yeah yeah I
think I found so many bugs that were so
easy but just like hidden in some
JavaScript calls that were made by the
front end because I didn't have the
privilege or anything and also what's
really interesting about the JS file is
that there is a lot of um uh calls that
hasn't been released in production yet
so it's behind a b testing and so if you
manage to detect those a b tests you
might end up with a new scope to play
with like a wider attack surface and
especially for companies that do
continuous development this is super
true so if you manage to change the AP
testing and look at all the JS files you
might end up with really simple
viabilities like the basic idore but
just because it was so hidden inside the
the scope uh you no one found it so yeah
definitely interesting monitoring those
monitoring those G endpoints has always
been you know the JS files and then like
I said taking that extra layer that's
always been on my to-do list for
automation you know soft core automation
I guess is like okay
um you know I'm really interested in
this one program I'm gonna set up an
automation system specifically designed
around their you know cycle their their
software development cycle and have that
that pushed out
um but yeah I was going to ask as well
um regarding you mentioned a a when we
were walking to head down the street to
the to the freaking uh Shrine earlier
today to meet up with friends
um you know you mentioned that there was
this vs code uh plug-in that that you
you've been using um and I imagine it
actually would work it well in
conjunction with JS weasel exactly and
yeah could you talk a little bit about
that because that was a really
interesting product yeah so uh I saw uh
the Tweet of Corbin that basically used
Jace weasel uh with cursor and cursor is
like a rapper around vs code uh since vs
codes is mostly open source and
basically they are embedding uh gpt4
inside the vs code and you can directly
ask questions about your code base
what's really interesting is that you
can pay
um the subscription but you can also
directly natively use your gpt4 API keys
so you will directly pay to open Ai and
no need to go through their servers and
um it's so amazing like uh right now I
I'm using it to do uh JavaScript
analysis on Google goal that they use
like a lot of RPC weird calls like it's
audible proprietary protocol yeah and
basically I'm going like okay that's the
inch point of the request right so what
are the parameters because they're like
so embedded in one function to another
function to another function and
basically I just asking the AI
um tell me which other function you want
context to so I can provide it to you
and we can reconstruct the requests and
I did that like maybe five six times and
at one point I just got the request that
I needed to send wow and then like the
pro to buff request and I was like oh
that's amazing and it just built it
automatically yeah wow and so I use JS
Wizzle to detect uh which like other
endpoints you did some automation also
to get the ideas right and then you just
ask cursor okay explain to me this code
and this is the job like instead of
having like six to seven hours of good
review you can do it like maybe in two
hours it's so great I love it wow it's
really interesting like I think this is
something before AI or like gbt was
really yeah more you know before was as
flushed out as it is this would be
something that you might have like code
ql or maybe some more of a technical
tool we'll be doing but this the
approach to basically just feeding it
into Ai and saying hey what do I need to
know about this it's so much more
powerful because it can do everything
just like in an instant where it just
analyzes this huge chunk of data and is
able to just parse it and tell you oh
yeah here's what you need to know
I'm a little I'm a little confused about
how that works though because I feel
like the code base would extend past the
context window any any I do either of
you guys know how that works or is it
with gpt4 like 8K or something I don't
know
um so uh basically when I use it I
select the lines of code that I wanted
to interpret but they natively use a way
to uh compress the file and basically
they have like some kind of if I
understood correctly a search engine on
the client side that uh that depending
on the question will go look for the
code before and then giving the context
to open AI so you do not have to give
everything I see it's like Bing search
is doing like the search engine uh does
the first request and then give the data
back to open Ai and open AI will uh put
contacts I see I see yeah that's really
interesting because like what you meant
we were talking earlier about like
tokens and and sort of how like AI looks
at input as token and it splits it up
into different segments that it can
understand better and sort of looks at
those pieces individually and then we'll
build like the context together and I
think that's like what you said like it
the way that it parses that is kind of
counterintuitive because you might think
like oh you know I can't feed a giant
filing but you can because it it can do
some more processing Magic on it than
that before
um I mean like llm are trained on so
many data points that actually they can
complete contexts uh so if you say this
function passes something they can guess
uh it's not like the the more accurate
way to do it but I think the cursor team
did a great job about knowing what to
feed to the AI and knowing like what
that I already know so you you can like
compress as much as possible the tokens
to not you know pay the 8K subscription
right right right
um yeah and I think combining those two
tools together JS weasel and and uh was
it cursor cursor okay like mouse cursor
yeah okay gotcha gotcha
um yeah combining those two tools
together is a really powerful combo so
shout out to Corbin for for that one um
uh yeah I'm I'm definitely I'm
definitely interested to see where all
that goes and JS weasel uh I think we'll
probably cover in a little bit more
detail on a different episode
um but I I booted it up for the first
time doing this live hacking event and
I've been using it and uh it's really
cool to see it do automatically what we
talked about you know breaking out those
those
um uh webpacked JS files and having it
you know drop all of the things there
um but I'm wondering I don't know if
you've used a Joel but for for you
Lupine
um I'm wondering uh how you've been
using the tool because for me I've been
having a little bit of a difficulty with
and I talked to Charlie about this and I
think he's fixing it but um I've been
having a little bit of difficulty with
identifying the portions of the JS code
that I really want to analyze because
there's not a search function presently
yeah
um and so I mean do you do you have that
same struggle have you worked around it
what how are you using the tool
currently yeah um the the tool misses
like a such uh function uh that that's
definitely something uh that that needs
to be implemented the way I use it is
more about like
um knowing dots act surface and the
constructing uh word list out of it so
uh basically I had
um this graphql
API that was behind the authentication
and so it was just for admins right but
you could with a low privileged user
just because uh you know cookies are
well why I can't get that you could make
a simple requests to it but with that
authorization of course and um
the introspection wasn't turned on okay
so how do you know which queries do you
do you go to the JS files right and what
I did with Jess Wizzle that was awesome
it listed all the queries I just copied
all the queries and uh generated word
lists that I gave to Clairvoyance right
and basically uh clavance which tries to
Brute Force the the schema the graphical
schema and give it back to you and so
then I fit the 70 MMO like it was a big
schema to graphical Voyager and I had
like everything every call that it was
being made because they like in when
there is a graph here everything is
always documented in the front end I
don't know why there is some libraries
that even have introspection inside the
JS like if it's not turned on go check
the JS and you can copy the
introspection and paste it just because
they forgot to turn the the flag and
never seen that yeah I I've seen like a
lot of times and it's so interesting
um so so it's so funny mention that
because I literally did the exact same
thing except I didn't use JS weasel for
it I used my own parsing script to you
know uh expand the webpack files yeah
and then I did exactly that I I took a
regex I pulled every string that was
compliant with uh graphql
um you know naming standards essentially
for for queries and for um for field
names and that sort of thing and put it
all in a word list and I fed it to
Clairvoyance
um and for those of you that are
listening that aren't familiar we'll
link it down below but Clairvoyance is a
is a um is a tool that uh I guess sort
of plays on the problem with graphql
where they will recommend you uh Fields
if you have the improperly uh defined
Fields so uh you know let's say you
there's a field called store and you
know I sometimes it's even like like
pretty pretty far like you might even
get away with like Sport and it might be
did you mean store yeah and it'll tell
you it really depends on the back end so
depending on the language you can set up
the amount of token that needs to to be
the same so really it's interesting yeah
so sometimes it's like two tokens apart
so two letters sometimes it's three four
uh and they can set up that on the
backhand side and depending on the
framework they will have a different
kind of uh far away or not you know yeah
well I mean it's really interesting that
you mentioned that that that started
with graphql because I was going to say
the same thing about not even just
graphql but same thing with API requests
like if yes if you're pulling apart
those webpack uh files in the lazy
loaded files not only will you see the
endpoints but you also see how they're
being used where is that data coming
from and one of the really powerful
things about having all of that just
right in front of you in JavaScript it's
just like Android apps where you know
you can decompile it you can see how
everything is working like right in
front of you you can do the same thing
with the JavaScript all you have to do
is pull it apart you can see oh it's
making a post request and it builds the
body with these fields yes they're named
this and that data comes from here it's
a parameter and that's fed in through
here and you can track it all and you
can see sort of how that data flows
through the application to get to that
request and you can piece it together
without ever having used the application
at all you can do it completely from
static analysis yeah yeah
um cool all right well but we went on a
little bit there um
I feel like we should at least have you
introduce yourself
listen I turned I turned it on you know
at the time that I did on purpose
um we'll we'll give you a little bit of
a pre-introduction on this episode but
yeah let's let's hear the self
instruction or the jiko shokai uh uh for
you Lupine
um
oh man uh yeah uh so uh um Ronnie also
known as dipping on the internet uh I've
been doing
um security since uh 13 years old uh
because I wanted to become like Austin
Lupine I knew a bit of programming and I
was I read the book of us in up and I
was like how can I become that guy at
the moment I read the book and I made
the association with programming I
thought I created the hacking uh but but
then I learned about all the history all
the culture from the 50s and everything
and I I love it so much I started yeah I
was gonna say how's that going I mean
are you looping I feel like you're
looping I feel like you've done that you
know like I mean uh Lupine is a
gentleman Thief I I'm not seeing from
anyone Maybe
busy seeing from companies like because
they're giving booty I don't know you're
the top Lupine that I'm aware of you
know when I think Lupine I think you not
anyone else thanks a lot and um and yeah
so I I and I started back into hunting
like two years and a half ago it's like
four years maybe I don't I don't
remember correctly but um and it has
been a wild ride uh started the live
hacking scenes uh one year ago in Vegas
and uh it's just amazing uh experience
it's awesome how did you how did you get
on the live hacking event scene did you
just get it did you just open your mail
one day and there was an invite or
um I think it was like the first
Ambassador World Cup uh because since
I'm uh an ambassador for France and
apparently I did well I I don't think so
uh but they gave me an invite uh to
Vegas uh we actually won the first World
Cup even though the second one we didn't
get the first like I think I did well
they won
[Laughter]
first round of the World Cup yeah and
it's just I don't know man sometimes
it's just
you know I'm not I'm not even gonna
throw any salt but it happens yeah it
happens no comment
and yeah um live hacking are way
different uh the backbone tea uh it's so
tiresome you get like one month's uh
straight of you know no social
interaction anymore you know going to
bed at 5am starting your day at 10 A.M
and you're like ah it's so interesting
seeing how how things have shifted in
the very early days of Life hacking
events it used to be I mean sometimes
you wouldn't even know the scope until
you got there yeah and uh and it would
just be like hack Fest everybody's just
like finding really cool bugs on the
same day and now it's evolved so that
there's like a pre-hacking window
there's a duplication window before
basically you know work 12 hours a day
sometimes more uh just every single day
leading up to the event finding all
these really really crazy bugs and then
they convene together and even more
crazy bugs get found because of the
mines connecting together and having
these awesome discussions between
hackers amazing something that Jonathan
said Jonathan Boomin uh
that I really liked is he said that he
wanted to have the show and tells before
the event starts on site to inspire
other people to find stuff and I think
it's an amazing idea so you imagine you
you two weeks down the rabbit hole you
didn't find anything and you have like
people showing you for bases like this
is how we've done it and like inspiring
you it's finding new stuff on site that
could be so awesome oh yeah that would
be that would be amazing and we always
walk away from the show and tells like
you know your brains are just buzzing
you know yeah and you're like oh man
maybe I could apply that here or there
and then and then you know you go out
and you know hit the bar or whatever and
then the next day you don't even check
it but yeah it uh that would be that
would that would be a really good idea
the last show entails in Vegas uh there
was France Frozen that had two show
entails back to back and so salty I
missed this yeah and uh and man like I I
went out of this rental with an attic uh
like because of him it was just so many
stuff going on and I was like what the
heck is he talking about and I I want to
go back again reading his reports let's
get better at it right because trentas
are like this you get creativity from
other people and you you don't need to
do what they did but you need to apply
what you learn for your own creativity
and I really like this format because of
that yeah I mean oftentimes I'd say it's
like maybe 25 75 like you know one third
like two-thirds kind of split or
whatever where I'll see a bug and I'll
be like oh I was looking at that thing I
I almost thought about trying that or
maybe I did try it and I just didn't
really push far enough and I was like I
just tried and I was like okay this
isn't gonna work I just moved on and
that ended up being a bug but so many
other times there'll be something
completely out of left field where I'm
like I never would have like never ever
would have tried anything like that and
I sort of have to take mental notes and
be like okay that's something that I
need to see if that's going to work sure
why did that work was it like a specific
system was it how it was set up what
went wrong in the back end to make that
happen there was um like my first event
in Vegas there was a great show and tell
from Tom Anthony and
um the the the the one in London there
was a customer that was the the same one
and I remember like uh this feature I
never hacked on that customer like on
the other event I hacked on the other
customer uh but I remember I mentioned a
really interesting feature and so I went
looking for that feature and I was like
that's interesting remember what it did
and like I was remembering like the bug
and everything and I found a bypass like
uh a simpler version but complex because
like it was a lot of parsing
requirements and stuff like that so the
payload was simpler but it was like so
hard to find and basically because of
his showing until I got like a bypass of
one of his verbitty from one year ago
and it was like that's the purpose of
trying to like getting new visibility
and new creativity you know yeah I think
I think that's something that we could
think about implementing in the
ambassador program as well the hacker
one ambassador program is like if we
yeah you you're the Ambassador for
France I'm the Ambassador for uh
Virginia
um and I think it would be really cool
after you know we go do a spree of
hacking to have a little show and tell
you know for our locality or whatever
that'd be really good and we'd learn a
little bit more uh you know from all the
other hackers and stuff like that no
um yeah we'll have to I have to think
about influence yeah brainstorming
session yeah okay okay so so
um
I guess bringing it back uh Lupine used
recently started a company called
looping in homes yeah
um beautiful website
ellenh.lnh.tech is that it is beautiful
website everything Lupine designs you
know or has designed is like super
gorgeous
um talk to me a little bit about that
company what your goals are for the
company how it relates to bug Bounty
that sort of thing
um so it really started uh like before
finding this company I was a senior
security engineer uh at manometers a
European uh company like Marketplace
online and uh I I entered that company
when I was 18 years old uh uh I did like
two years there and I learned so much
and I learned also like what the the
purpose of research in security and how
it can be applied uh to companies and
from that learning I was like I need to
do more uh research in security right
okay I'm gonna I'm gonna interrupt and
then we're gonna come back to that so
actually you know you're you're you said
you were at manamano you joined when you
were 18. yeah and then you left like
when when I was 20 21 21 yeah and which
is now yeah okay yeah and and you what
was your title at monomano uh senior
security engineer okay gotcha wow so you
see how the heck did an 18 year old just
jump right into big Marketplace and get
to be a secure how did that work like
what was that process
so
um basically I I was never good at
school I always hated it uh it's a good
sign yeah
yeah
and um but I I always wanted to do a
creative job right and I I was hacking
and and someone introduced me to um bug
Bunty right actually it was I like my
teacher that told me hey there's this
CTF do you want to participate and yeah
in high school yeah uh it was like a
European CTF the the ciso for high
schoolers from all around Europe and I I
brought like two friends with me and I
told them you do not have to play the
CDF I just need people for my team to go
there like to to put someone on the list
and uh we we qualified to the finals and
there was uh all the conferences and
stuff and there was a conference from
yes weak right they were telling hey you
can actually get paid for finding
security Barbados and I was like that's
legal that's awesome yeah
and so I got back at home and I was like
okay what is back burning
and you could disclose vulnerabilities
and that's the only reason I went online
ironically yes we are gave me the idea
to go on hack one yes
[Laughter]
uh but uh yeah I really like the
disclosure because actually you you
could share vulnerabilities and you
could prove uh your experience yeah
right and so I started backbend tea
hunting it was hard at the beginning but
because of the reputation and the fact
that you have a public profile I use
that as my CV my resume and I showed
companies that hey I actually managed to
hack those big companies and uh I have
the technical skills right and you know
I've done some research there was stuff
published in the media I did some
interviews into television visibility
also helps and um all of that like one
day A friend of mine uh Zach's uh told
me hey there is uh this company that
will hire a security engineer uh they
didn't open the the job yet but I
recommended you and like two days
afterwards I got a ping and I they
actually hired me before the job was
open wow and uh actually based only off
of a recommendation or did you do an
interview I did I did an interview I
like I did several interviews with the
team they saw his work and they're like
we need to hire this guy I did several
interviews they were great really funny
interviews actually and the jewels that
was my manager another one that you know
but like uh he he was so great with me
he's also really young at the time I
think he was 24 and he was my manager
and I was his first employee and we had
like a great relationship it really
helped me grow and you know that led to
research into creating my own company so
basically my brother has like a similar
stories with studies uh he never uh like
he did seven years of first years of
college right he was seven times yeah
she like because he was bored of it and
so he did like actually uh the first
years of my older brothers in low like
in Lowe's stuff and in philosophy and he
never liked anything but my father one
day said hey you don't know anything
about programming about development yeah
you barely know how to use a computer
but there is like the 42 school network
that opened like it was like really new
at the time in 2017 I think and he said
uh to him go do that school and
basically it's a school without teachers
there is no courses like you just have
exercises uh of programming and you do
not need to know programming to get into
that school it's 100 free and the school
is open 24 7. wow so to get into that
school you need to pass a logical test
and then you have something called the
piscin which is the pool okay and the
pool basically you have one month of
intensive programming where you need to
learn from scratch to become like an
expert in C and C plus oh wow okay which
is horrible horrible yeah and if
you all the tests
in the school okay right so it's
hardcore mode you need to try out and
what's like what's sort of the incentive
to to like pass that test is there some
sort of like is it very exclusive is
there like a certain like once you're
there it helps you get a better job or
why why would people want to push
through that and learn C and C plus plus
and stuff in order to get there you'll
learn so much in a condensed uh time so
in one month you actually know how to
program fully in CNC plus which is
astonishing yeah what they managed to do
and in one year you can get a job for
the like the the better students or
otherwise in two three years but you do
not need any degrees and you will get
hired by companies so that's the
incentive like you do not know what to
do with your life go to that school if
you like remotely computers yeah and he
actually did and he became like a good
back-end developer like but like really
good and um he he works for many
different startups and you know so we
were talking and you know showing
knowledge about you know our jobs and
one time we're like I do research in
security user development we need to do
something yeah we need to do something
together and so we wanted to create that
r d company and because my nickname was
Lupine we needed to find a nickname for
him and like Holmes was the perfect one
like Sherlock yeah and it goes really
good with him because uh I guess homes
use the deduction like when you are
programming you need to you know find
the best path to create something yeah
and homes are really like that and also
my brother do not like to talk in the
Medias I do not like the fame he he
exactly like Sherlock Holmes and we're
like this is like the great persona for
him right yeah and so Lupine Holmes is
really about you know trying to complete
one another we are opposite sides but
like oh the opposite of a coin right we
we just yeah yeah they must be together
but never at the same time exactly and
so I I use bug Bunty as a way to do
research and then everything that I
learned from bug Bunty about you know
maybe fixing about abilities or finding
the vomitis I then asked my brother to
code tools and then those tools are
going to be on products that we are
going to sell to companies maybe to bug
Hunters but mostly for companies so so
you've got uh you know on that line
you've got a secret product that that we
won't talk about on on this episode but
we will be talking about on a future
episode and uh and your brother is is
primarily doing the the coding for that
yeah I didn't know the entire back end
wow um and it it's it's pretty good
because
um sometimes I ask him to do something
uh security related he's like why like
why would anyone try that and I'm like
that's the whole purpose of the research
exactly yeah that that's great um yeah
the and so I guess how is it with you
then
um working with somebody else's code
because for me like especially within my
automation framework I feel like I need
to know the ins and outs of it and even
sometimes when I don't when I look at a
piece of code that I wrote like three
years ago four years ago it's like you
know who the frick wrote this yeah you
know before Joel started influencing my
Python Programming uh so I mean has that
has that worked all right for you I mean
have you written any of the code
yourself every time some of the codes uh
mostly for the clients uh but not uh for
the back ends um I think it's better if
I do not touch the code
that's what he tells you at least yeah
yeah
definitely
yeah and it's more like we need to
separate our jobs like my job is to
actually find new ways to do research
and his job is to develop and it's
actually good that I do not touch the
code because I'm doing like a bit of the
product manager like I ask things that
are not possible and he needs to find a
way to do them yeah I actually love that
that sort of um that separation of roles
where normally you would say like
research and development is sort of like
globbed into one thing where you know
you're doing research and you're
developing but research and right like
one of you is doing research one of you
is doing development and it sort of
allows you to have a singular focus and
really hone in on that because one of
the things that we've talked about is
um you know there's the xkcd right where
it's about Automation and it's you know
over time all of your time starts to get
taken up by having to maintain and man
and that is going to take away from the
amount of time that you have to do
research and actually learn new things
learn new techniques and explore and
find new bugs and that kind of stuff and
so if you can separate that out and say
here you manage with the development all
manage with the research that really
allows each of you to sort of hone in
that craft to 100 I always take an
example of a proof of concept that we're
doing right now uh basically there was
like this Target that is really known
for applying the xss and I was like we
need to find a way to automate buying
exercise but not in the way that do dumb
automation about just you know putting
everything out there and just see what
will happen but like
you know try to find the right payload
for the right context and this is hard
but I know that some Hunters are really
good at understanding how the panel like
admin panel size works right and they
know the right payload to it and I was
like we can do some detection out of it
right and so I asked him to create a
semi-automation tool so I not I don't
like to automate everything I like to
you know understand what I'm doing and
to have you know hands on everything
happening on the process but there are
things that you know like finding the
right payload and putting it writing it
again or copy pasting it takes so much
time and so we created like this blind
access framework where basically you can
put templates and you have your own
config files and you can actually put
you know in the request templates it
would do some smart match and replace to
actually put the right payload and so
you do not need to know the payload just
create your templates and you go for it
and this tool is highly module and right
now we are giving it to a few back
Hunters too yeah
to test it and see like
what people need out of it one feature
that I really would like to to do is
that uh creating data flows like request
flows but it better said uh where for
instance there is blind exercise that
may happen in the checkout right and
that's something it's really hard to
automate yeah and what I want to do is
like from the login up to the checkout
you could record all the the requests
right and so replay all the requests and
logging in adding a product going to
check exactly and then but you modify
one request at a time and
um if the request is not uh like since
you record the request and response if
the response is not expected you drop
the entire flow and you start from the
beginning with a new request almost like
fuzzing almost like fuzzing but in a way
that you keep the logic of you know
adding a product in your cart and then
from the I guess you are pay I should
have said more like symbolic execution
where it's like you have a certain flow
and you say it has to meet all of this
specific criteria and it's like so this
is a success case exactly so I'm a
little bit uh Curious how does that that
flow correlate to Blind xss are you
trying to get the application into
different states where you think that it
may trigger some sort of uh appearance
in a log log on the admin panel or
something like that or there was a
research for some from someone that was
really interesting about um using log4j
like trying to trigger lock 4J uh
payloads but in a real weird situation
and basically like the research was
about doing error based uh requests so
you will trigger a lot of requests you
will try to you know get banned your IP
band stuff like that and put you know
beacons in the header and stuff like
that everything that the app shouldn't
do you try to do it in order to generate
a log and those kind of flows I am
saying like for like an incident or
something like that like some someone
look at this guy he's doing something
weird and then exactly and Dara will
trigger the the flow uh for instance you
have a checkout page and you put a
product imagine maybe imagine that the
API you can change the product name or
the card's name and that's that you know
you need to test those kind of thing but
it takes so much time to test all the
different possibilities that my dream
will be to have those data flow and when
you say possibilities do you mean
because this is going back to what
you're saying earlier about a payload
are you talking about like payload like
like using a polyglot payload for like
where it will trigger on admin side are
you talking about the entry point like
Department
you're saying okay you know login add a
product
um go to the cart uh change the cart
names you know submit the order exactly
and then the payloads in the cart name
and then exactly go back to it again and
then at this time yeah
exactly gotcha very cool yeah that would
be really cool automated flow yeah uh
we're still working on that uh it's a
lot of work and especially yeah yeah
very difficult it's interesting because
was um one I'm a little ashamed to admit
this but I haven't I didn't even use
nuclei or like httpx or anything until
like a couple weeks ago and um I I think
one of the things that really pushed me
over the edge to start doing that is
that I like you did basically entirely
manual testing for a very long time I I
would focus on specific things I would
see weird behavior and I would chase
that down and I came to a point where I
realized like I'm I need to do more
breadth but it doesn't have to be
necessarily in depth like if I just want
to identify oh this host is online I
don't have to go open 15 tabs I can just
run a tool that does that automatically
and make my life a little bit easier and
then maybe I can do some manual testing
to figure it out or I can take a polygon
Glock payload or or you know a tool like
what you're writing and use that to even
go one step further and narrow down my
scope even more but yeah well go ahead
yeah uh what what's interesting about
automation is that there is in my
opinion three ways of doing background
to you yeah you have full manual so you
just check the request one by one this
is exactly what I was gonna say good
good there is full automation
uh where you basically trust your
servers and computers to do everything
and there is like where I kind of sit uh
semi automation yeah so my problem with
automation is that it's not becoming
like about getting creative with
Mobility understanding scope it's about
doing a race uh against all the people
that does automation right you do not
need to have the most accurate results
you need to be the first one right right
uh for instance the subem sub domain
takeover scene is really like that right
now so if someone has a specific
Automation and someone maybe know how to
code and go or rust this person will get
the subdomain first right right and
that's not in the way that I like to do
hacking but you can be really good at it
right right there is manual testing
where it's really long you need to go
thorough you made a tweet about you know
knowing the application until you get
sick of it yes yes and I'm sick of
getting sick of it yes yes 100 yeah and
because it's such a grind like I think
exactly we've talked about this a lot
like you have to get intimate with the
application right gotta get intimate
with it but that I mean some
applications the amount of features the
amount of depth there is to an
application that can take weeks maybe
even months to fully understand every
little piece every I mean I'm thinking
about like
it's a great example where I mean such a
huge complicated application where yeah
it can take so long to get a full grasp
of how does this thing work how do these
systems connect together and if you
aren't using tools to your advantage to
sort of just take you know jump up five
stairs up up or whatever right like you
just have to kind of use some of the
tools that are out there because even
though it might feel like uh you know I
really want to just do this manually I
don't want to you know let the tools
tell me what to do you know it's really
worth it it's worth your time and it's
worth the amount of effort and energy
that you're going to spend you know days
weeks whatever it would just learn that
application just to you know get one
step ahead because you know the
subdomain uh takeover is a great example
I know tons of people who do automation
for that kind of stuff and that's not
really what my focus is right like I
understand like yeah you could maybe
code up a really fast example but you're
starting at the beginning compared to
all these people who've been automating
for a very long time they're already
multiple steps ahead and instead you
could focus on something that is deeper
that the automation is not necessarily
going to pick up but you can get there
by taking a couple shortcuts right you
have to learn some of the the you know
Nuance to that application without
having to go through the whole manual
process yeah and from the very beginning
uh I think about it kind of like
learning a language right this is a
great example
you've been in Japanese
instead of you know learning one word at
a time and then we're learning two
thousand words then being like okay now
I'm gonna try and say hello my name is
Joe like it's like learn hello my name
right hello my name is the pieces that
actually help you in your daily life
that's like a really good example with
Japanese is that instead of
understanding like every word uh and
what I'm trying to do is actually say
sentences that I will use during my trip
like for instance uh I want this thing
and that's it like I do not need to know
everything but she's been learning
Japanese for like four days
very very very fast like like he picked
it up so fast oh yeah I I I can't have a
discussion yet that's my goal in two
weeks you know uh but but yeah like this
is a good example for instance uh you
also like with semi-automation you need
to know what is worth automating yeah
for instance uh yesterday we were
looking uh with Justin
um on Google and Google has a lot of
property protocols and uh is it worth
automating at one point we were asking
this question this application we want
we want I asked you this exactly I was
like Lupine is this you know we we read
a great write-up on essentially how it
works which will which will link yeah
and uh and we're like okay so do we want
to build a you know essentially a burp
extension surrounding uh making this
much easier to test or do we want to
just look at look at you know take our
knowledge of the protocol and
essentially just every single time uh
burn that Edition General mental Cycles
you know translate in our brain to you
know what we're seeing and and that was
a discussion we had and I think that's a
really important discussion to have for
automation
um yesterday we landed on building the
automation because we uh that that those
mental Cycles uh really inhibit uh
creativity and hacking and this is
something we talk about on the podcast a
lot but anytime you can reduce friction
to to testing
um you know you want to be able to
ideally in an Ideal World you want to be
able to have an idea oh what if I did
this yeah and then test that immediately
yeah yeah and and that's what we're kind
of shooting for with that so yeah it's
exciting for sure what's really
interesting about this specific
application and why we went on the
automation route of it is because this
application use this Google Preparatory
protocol uh called batch execute to
doing RPC school but this is not the
only application that use this protocol
right and so basically if we build the
automation with that specific app in
example like for instance you when like
for manual testing and I went from
automating what he learned from the
manual testing and so if we have a good
proof of concept with that application
every other Google application using
that protocol we will be able to assess
it faster and to understand it better
and so that's what was the reason why
we're coming for you Google
and that was the reason why the
automation made sense but at the same
time we didn't went on the route of okay
we're going to get all the requests from
the JavaScript and then play it and pass
them it's just like getting all the
requests and
having like a template of what to send
and then we can do manual testing yeah
so we Save hours of reverse engineering
in the JavaScript to for concentrating
only on the creativity part yes not the
searching but on the hey is that uh
pollution on that parameter uh what if I
put this ID here you know that kind of
stuff yeah and and I want to say as well
it it just before we jumped into
something else but the
you it's it's very tempting to think
about it like a math equation like okay
um am I going to save brain sort of CPU
Cycles by by you know spending let's say
three hours up front to build the
automation right uh is that Gonna Save
Me three hours worth of time and I I
thought about it like that for a while
but then I realized this is really not
uh the best way to think about it
because precisely we're not catching and
quantifying that whole piece of like how
much it's inhibiting our creativity or
inhibiting our our attack Vector
formulation to constantly be having to
all right now I got a URL encode this
and I gotta stick this in this little
Json blob and ah I gotta fix the
escaping and bloody bloody blah yeah and
so you know uh I think oftentimes like
that especially when you're committing
to a target for a longer period of time
um even if you think you won't
necessarily get that time back you will
get Roi on that because your brain will
work more efficiently in that
environment that's true yeah 100 I've
also done some hacking on Google
um maybe like a month ago and I ran into
a very very similar situation where
um just like the entry point to hacking
it can be very difficult because of
these specific protocols and these weird
formats that they use and so it's not so
much that you're building out like a
tool that's going to automate the entire
thing yeah but it's really almost just
like a helper script right it's like in
the same way that burp has a pretty Tab
and a raw tab right you can just make it
format it for you you can make it decode
that for you or make it readable for you
so that when you hover over the
requester when you're scrolling through
you can identify and you can pattern
match manually significantly faster and
easier than you would by doing it over
and over again manually and being like
hold on where's that uh weird bite that
I'm looking for okay there's the there's
the type and you know just that is very
mentally draining and it's just like
having you know like sometimes I'll do
it with python I'll just write like a
little function or a script or something
and I'll have it in my terminal and I'll
just I'll just have it like read from my
clipboard or something to do it
automatically and that's so much easier
than than like writing an entire piece
of tooling definitely yeah actually Joel
I I steal it from you because I actually
want you to talk about that a little bit
because that's like one of the coolest
things that I've seen about your hacking
methodology so essentially please expand
but he's got a set of functions that
he's built over time and then you
essentially just open up the python
terminal it reads from the clipboard and
then you you can kind of chain together
these automations right 100 I have a
little module I call Pi hack and
basically whenever I I use IPython as my
terminal and essentially I'll just
import this file and it has a bunch of
little they're like aliases like bash
aliases for me but they're more complex
and it's easier for me to write in
Python than it is in bash and it'll do
stuff like URL decode or slash Escape
like a common scenario is I'll copy
something that has slash ends in it
right and I want to see it without I
want to see them literally as slash so I
have a just a little helper function
that takes them decodes them and prints
it out manually and does this make it
like so much easier
um HTML decoding uh hex encoding hex
decode like and just little tiny helper
things things to group stuff these are
the types of like very little you know
Nuance that makes it so much easier and
you have them for everything yeah all
sorts of things yeah like like every
single time I'm like oh okay Joe's gonna
have to code so like because because we
we pair hack you know from time to time
so like uh you know I see your screen
you know when you do this and I'm like
all right this time he's gonna have to
do like some like dot replace [__] or
something like that yeah no every single
time you've got a function for it yes
yeah yeah on that on that note on the
pair hacking I was sitting in front of
them uh at the PayPal event
it's just the best thing ever to watch
them both of them all day on one single
problem oh my God I haven't seen that
many years of muscular faces over the
day like both of them were like
[Laughter]
oh no yes no
that was just so funny but you guys
recomplete one another and I I think it
really works well for you yeah I think
pair hacking works specifically well for
for Joel and I like uh I think I think
uh I like to say it I I point Joel you
know at the thing like Joel brain power
that you know like to be honest I think
that like every person's idea doing
badminton needs a uh bear hacker with
them and that's what we've seen in the
top uh backbending Hunter Community like
if you see uh Franz Frozen Master
skeleton if you see Jonathan there's
Sean yeah and like everyone is uh like
there is one hacker yeah always with you
100 yeah I mean it's like so we've
always said like two brains are better
than one and this doesn't have to be an
in-person thing I think one of the
advantages of being in person is that
you can
feed off of each other like we don't
even like there'll be things that we
just don't even like talk like we'll
just be like looking at the same thing
and we'll be picking up things at the
same pace and I'll be like oh did you
see that and you'll be like yeah yeah
that's really interesting and it's like
what's that right but it's like we're
just sort of on that level where yeah
we're able to sort of go and when you
get to that point your efficiency is
literally 2X or more because you have
two people two two perspectives like he
has seen things that I haven't seen I've
seen things that he hasn't seen I know
techniques that he doesn't know he knows
that he said I don't know you've got
little scripts that can encode things
faster and I care right and he knows
like he's like oh just here do this you
know I found it like just run this thing
and I'm like what I don't even know how
this works whatever I'll just run it
like last time in Vegas I met Madison
Wisconsin and we were talking about that
and he told me what you need to do is to
find someone with the same technical
skill as you yeah uh but at the same
time that can complete you like you do
not need a mentor her you need some
someone to grow with you right and like
that that's something that a lot of
beginners uh have trouble with is that
oh I need someone to learn from and
that's not the fact like you need
someone to learn with yes in order to
grow up together and I think that's the
best best part of hacking when you can
just you know critical things right
right hey honestly honestly one of the
most amazing things that I see
especially with like Mentor
relationships it's not always like
mentors us so many times I'll be
mentoring like someone who's new to bug
Bounty and they will ask what might seem
as a simple question but I'm like why
haven't I ever thought about that like
why why like I just made like some sort
of assumption because I was you know I
was I'm more advanced and I I just like
was like oh it's definitely going to
behave this way and the beginner will be
like is it going to behave that way and
I'm like yeah actually is it right like
I should probably look and check and
that again it's like you are learning
with them you're growing together it's
not just like oh let me teach you this
right like some of it is that but it's
also you have to feed off of each other
and be willing to to open and change
your perspective and learn new
techniques yeah uh that that's actually
how I learn
um hiking like uh I went on discords
like beginner discords because I was a
beginner at the time and all the
questions that the beginners I was
trying to answer them but not like I was
doing the rtfm for them and I was like
but I was like all the questions that
they have is a question that I will have
and if I can answer them right now when
I will confront it it will be easier for
me that's great yeah and I think that's
like if you do not have anyone uh to to
learn with it's great to do it that way
because you have like so much question
from all over the people like you know
getting access to attack surface that
you do not have like for instance hey
what is this protocol hey what is this
can you hack it and like I I just went
like grinding for like three four
monthses and by the end of the day you
get actually like a good skills about
what an attack surface is and when you
are going on back burning hunting it's
easier for you and you feel safer yeah
so much of this goes back to like when I
try and describe how you should be
picking up hacking yeah it's really you
should be in the beginning question
everything right like yeah what is HTTP
what what is this get slash HTTP slash
one point what does this mean like what
is this structure why does it look this
way how does it behave how does it get
interpreted when I when I click a button
what's happening oh man and like just
breaking that down and understanding it
at a like a fundamental level builds
those core building blocks that you can
then use forever right just like what
you said like building out a tooling
that will make your life easier when
you're testing some specific protocol it
just sets the ground floor so so that
you can go up from there and you have a
solid foundation that that that happened
to me uh when I was trying to use a
bypass for ssrf and uh basically I went
you know on the cheat sheet and uh and
took like a octal uh bypass like
basically the IPS in Auto formats and
you put it and I was like what is this
format and so I went directly at the
source the Corvette the RFC of Ip and it
started at 6 p.m and ended up at 5am the
freaking Rabbit Hole of what hack is an
IEP but by the end of the day it helped
me so much to bypass uh stuff because an
IP can be so many things it just needs
to be a 32-bit integer but they do not
specify how like if it's an extra
decimal in octal uh like the point that
the four dots format is just you know a
convention but I actually
every color needs to interpret all the
different kind of formats which is
insane and when you know that you know
how to actually bypass uh those kind of
absolutely and and those sort of those
sort of tricks are are the only you know
you're gonna find those tricks by diving
deep and getting and getting far into
those yeah we had a thread uh really
recently like you went you just gave me
a a domain and said oh there's an
exercise on it just try to find it and
like one hour later I was like oh that
was a really cool challenge but we
didn't have like the we didn't have the
same answer to that challenge and like
we looked at it and like why your pillar
works yeah and actually created a lot of
debates on Twitter yeah I actually saw
something like this recently somebody
made a made a great Twitter post we'll
have to find it I don't remember who it
was but they they showed an example of a
command injection yeah where you could
encode the command in this really really
weird yeah it was like there was like
backslashes before each letter and it's
like all sorts of weird things I was
like I looked at I was like how how the
heck does this even work yeah and I
actually bookmarked it because I need to
go back later and I need to figure out
how it works and it's one of those
things where you're like if you can
figure out fundamentally how this works
the the fundamental parts of why it's
working and what's going on there apply
in other scenarios you don't have to do
it exactly like the exact same way but
you can use those pieces together to
build it to build it and I think this is
a great transition because you you made
a video recently about uuid V1 and you
want to talk about like deep dive and
like understanding like weird Nuance in
something that seems very typical
uuidv1 versus uuib uuidb through two
three four it's it's a lot of nuance in
there so can you talk a little bit about
that yeah definitely
um so I was hacking with Snorlax like uh
you know the French team we really hack
a lot together and
um these targets we re-hamaed it for uh
monsters and monsters right and we knew
everything and uh this I got had
everything in scope so even third
parties and uh Acquisitions and so we
were on this new acquisition that wasn't
that that wasn't explicit in scope and
um he was like huh that's weird like uh
the password reset is on another domain
and it just linked it to me and I was
like
wait a minute that's a uadv1 and why did
I trigger is because I don't know why
and I don't know how but for I think it
was because I was programming something
that needed uid I was like what's the
difference between V4 and V1 right uh
actually it's because at final manner we
were fixing a third party stuff that had
collisioned with before and I was like
what's the difference with uid anyway
and I found this blog post from a verse
price team uh actually talking about
View and everyone being generated on on
timestamps and I was like that doesn't
seem scared and it doesn't like just use
timestamps it also use the MAC address
and the clock ID of the machine so the
MAC address is basically the MAC address
and access the similar format so if the
same machine generate two ideas it will
say the same the clock ID is the same
it's a value that is set at the creation
of a machine like the first Boot and it
will always stay the same so you
actually have like two chunks of the uid
that always stay the same and the last
chance are the version so if it's a uid
V1 you will see that the third chunk the
first number will be the version so it's
one two three four five but the first
first thing I look at whenever I say
uuid is like third octet first character
and if it's a four I go and if it's a
one I go oh yeah exactly and so uh and
when you see one you know that it's
generated on timestamps right and so
then you see that the the third chunk is
actually the high and then you have the
mid and the low and I don't know exactly
why they are called like that but when
you are put together like uh you you
just concaten them it's it's doing
hexadecimal value and this this exciting
similar value when you put it in decimal
give you a time step in the Julian
calendar so I went on the internet
searching why did you run Canada find
the reason it like why the heck would
you use that use Epoch like normal
people
and and then you can you know go do some
basic math I'm really bad at math so of
course those have to be basic and uh to
to put it in the epoch timestamp and
then you get the date with a normal
converter and like you you can have like
some kind of disclosure of when this
idea has been generated right and now
they use uidv1 for the password reset
and UAV one since you can know the time
that have been generated and you can
reconstruct them really easily because
it's just you know uh trying to uh do
plus one in the hexadecimal values uh
you can actually do something called the
sandwich attack so basically you
generate
um a password reset for the attacker
then you generate one uh for your victim
and against the attacker and the
attacker pile is the layer of bread and
the victim is like the ham the garden
Church everything and you basically
sandwiched the reset token of a victim
between your two uh tokens yes and
someone asked me why do you need the
other layer like you can just put the
first one and the the victim one and you
can just Brute Force until you have the
victim it's just to give you
um a sense about if your script is
working like if you go over yeah if you
go over that value it means that you
didn't find the ID right right and so
there is another thing going on right so
that's why it's better to sandwich yeah
that's awesome so much of this reminds
me of ctfs CTF like security ctfs do
such a good job with these weird these
weird things stuff like UE one is a
great example where there's weird Nuance
to how things that might seem intuitive
of work and that makes it perfect for a
CTF where it'll be like hey look at this
piece of code this looks completely
normal but what's wrong with it yeah
right and you have to go wait a second
yeah what is wrong with this oh it's
uuidv1 and why is that vulnerable oh
because you can you know you can use
timestamps and you can predict the next
the next value and so forth and having
that type of training
um even though it's not like a bug
Bounty it's very very related and it
builds some of that like fundamental
knowledge and the understanding of those
weird Technologies which honestly
they're weird but they're used in the
real world so often that it's not like a
useless thing to know it's it's a very
very useful powerful piece of thing to
learn and also yeah I was so I was just
going to ask about that like
um when when you're when you're
there is a really cool comment on on the
the Twitter post yeah for that and
essentially it was saying
um using the new smashing the state
stuff
so okay well we'll say for those that
are listening I haven't seen it uh one
of the comments on Twitter said using
the Smashing the state
um research that James Kettle recently
released
um you should be able to get sub one
millisecond sure
um uh you know almost collisions with
your requests right they can be
processed within the same millisecond uh
assuming that that process is generating
a uuid V1
um uuid do you know if they will collide
or how how will that work do you know
um so uh uidv ones uh are on the
nanoseconds uh okay so no never
James do your [__] and make it faster
James
I mean my collabor like I I I I I I
don't really know the probability of
that uh but I think that was a really
interesting comment because
um that's basically obviously like the
article from Jazz cattle about uh so you
want to be a security researcher and he
says you need to go uh hunt for [__]
knowledge so stuff that other people
missed like for many many years for
instance tennis rebinding 2005. everyone
was using the dance for binding and then
he got lost and someone was like What if
it works on the client side
like of browsers and like it's reminding
that yeah that makes me remember
something yeah that name in years and
try to create diversity from this
forgotten knowledge so basically uh this
applied the logic of a vulnerability to
other type of Technologies and stuff
like that that digital surviving is a
prime example of that and then uh you
have
to get outside of your comfort zone your
own comfort zone is the same as many
other people and so if you get outside
with confidence you will be on untouched
territory and this kind of comments
about hey can we take this research and
this other research and smash it
together go for it no idea is stupid
until proven wrong and so I thought that
this comment was so great uh and uh
kudos to the person I've thought about
totally totally agree with that um yeah
always looking for those sort of
opportunities to combine those two
pieces together and generate something
new
um so I we're getting close to we're
getting closer to that what time is it
actually
the 10 45 okay we need to wrap up soon
but I did want to ask
um one last thing regarding your you
know experiences at live hacking events
um like you said we we all have you know
these people that we collaborate with
that help uh and that you know we kind
of complete right and and complete us
um so you collaborate uh often with the
the French team yeah can you talk a
little bit about the Dynamics and what
kind of lessons you've learned from that
collaboration yeah
um the French team is uh is super great
we didn't have a better name than just
the French team so
[Music]
the bucket dude that's it that's it okay
I'm going to bring some with them
that'll be great yeah and um yeah we
have an interesting dinner I'm actually
really proud of that
oh man the royalties are going to be
expensive
um it's actually really great because on
every live hacking event we always
manage to invite one of uh the team yeah
and what's interesting is that um the
team is composed like I think of five
people so we have Zoomer Zacks that uh
they both work uh the busy beezid aren't
they created the company uh we have
Snorlax who is an amazing Hunter uh
there is a bonsoade who is an upcomer
but like he did some amazing job with
openc everything yeah yeah yeah Chris
after Chris right yeah and uh there is
me and again which speaks for itself
and uh you know me of course and
needless to say I'm saying that because
um we are so different in our ways to
hunt uh for instance zax is is really
methodological about the way like he
does he does everything on the checklist
like I'm going to check that then that
then that Doomer is really good at
spreading and finding attack surfaces
Snorlax is really good about uh you know
Finding specific vulnerabilities and
also finding some weird stuff and I'm I
think I'm good about uh finding new
research and so what happened is that
snorlaxena and I it's like a
Counter-Strike uh esport Team like we we
are it's not like the pivot like we are
going on another Direction while they
are hunting on the main scope right and
we are like doing some crazy weird stuff
and once we find something interesting
we give it to them to first to Doomer to
find an attack surface and to spread
this vulnerability everywhere and then
to uh Zach to add to the checklist of
things to to check and everything this
reminds me of I mean shelves is a great
example because his Recon game is insane
and he'll just find like 15 different
like weird things and he'll be like hey
man I have this weird thing like do you
want to go check it out I'm like yeah
yeah and just like how Justin was saying
oh I'll like Point Joel in the right
direction it's very much so like that
where like you'll find a lead and you'll
be like I think we can get this but like
let me let you take a crack at it
because I know you can do it chefs is
like you get a weird thing you get a
weird thing
I love it but but yeah like um the way
the Dynamics works we are everyone each
one of us have their own role and the
counter strikes team is amazing because
it is like this is the a good example
because you have the guys doing the
entry points you have the other one
doing the support and you have like the
lurkers that's going to another
Direction and that's basically what
we're trying to apply uh within the team
we do not want to be on you know all
looking at the same thing we want
overlapping yeah overlapping and um for
instance at the epic games event at the
beginning of the year
um we were all looking at different
stuff and there was like this moment
where hey I got this thing working do
you think that on your scopic would work
and we spread it that [__] everywhere
and it works everywhere and that's the
dynamic like we we want to do and we do
not any overall so that works great and
also we are like really really great
friends and we love to yeah you know
when we're hunting 10 days in a row not
sleeping the the last day we have mental
breakdown and just at 2 am not managing
to write a report and like just someone
breathing to the microphone makes us
laugh for hours and hours and well like
this is like the greatest thing ever
about like being with your friends and
not just you know working you know
it's definitely an amazing experience
and I wanna I wanna talk you know
because last last time maybe his last
episode or the episode before I talked a
little bit about some of the
difficulties of collaboration just to be
clear I am not you know against I'm not
anti-collaboration I just think that
there are some challenges and it seems
like you and and some of the other
people that have you know been doing
collaboration successfully consistently
have really ironed out those details and
I think that's that's awesome and if you
do it in a way that's intentional and
aligns with everyone's goals then it
rocks and I experienced that as well so
yeah it's uh it's great to see you you
doing that what I like Chris
collaboration like I like to do for
instance when I'm not collaborating with
the French team is that for the
beginning I said I say like hoju on to
collaboration how do you want to play it
and before even finding probabilities so
use everything straight and what I like
to do is even if the other person do not
find anything but I know that they're
actually searching I want to still give
them 50 of of the report because I know
that if I continue collaborating with
that person and that if I trust the
person yeah
they will do the same thing for me and
we're going to balance out burnt is over
the time yeah and that's you know how
you create real Bond and friendship it's
not about money it's about you know
having human interaction with one
another interesting exactly awesome well
that was I think that's like a perfect
note to edit on I mean yeah is there
anything you want to shout out obviously
your company what is it l and H or Ln
and arms l i a n d h dot take care for
the website I just wanted to say thank
you guys for everything you've been
doing on the podcast it's just amazing
all the debates that is created
I love it that's why we need it in the
community so shout out to you guys for
everything you've been doing yeah well
thank you for being on we really
appreciate it and um yeah that's the
part right foreign
[Music]